# Yusril Albi

# Back End Engineer | Machine Learning Engineer | Data Engineerr

vusrilalbi.pro@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/yusrilalbi | https://yusrilalbi.my.id

DKI Jakarta | +6281273032294 | https://wa.me/6281273032294

### **SUMMARY**

I am an accomplished student with a scholarship background throughout my university studies. As a Back-End Engineer trainee at Shopee, I gained practical experience, and my time at Petronas equipped me with machine learning expertise. Serving as a Data Engineer at BRI, I contributed to data-driven solutions. Backed by multiple certificates, I have successfully executed projects involving Restful API, Time Series data, Web Scrapping, and lead project by project in my career, showcasing my versatility and problem-solving skills.

### **EDUCATIONS**

**Bangkit Academy led by Google** 

Machine Learning **Universitas Pertamina** 

Bachelor of Computer Science (Graduating with Cumlaude), Full Scholarship Invitation

Informatics Competition & Competitive Programming

• 1st Place in OSSN

• 1st Place in FUSC

• 1st Place in FOHKN

• 1st Place in Olimpiade Sains Mahasiswa (OSM)

• 1st Place in BIMAGE Competition

• Honorable Mention in Hology 4.0

#### **EXPERIENCES**

PT Shopee Internasional - Indonesia

Back End Engineer - Trainee

PT Petroliam Nasional Berhad (Petronas)

Machine Learning Engineer PT Bank Rakyat Indonesia (BRI)

Data Engineer - Intern

**Service Education DKI Jakarta** 

**Mentor Informatics** 

Jakarta, Indonesia Aug 2023 - Nov 2023 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Mar 2023 - Aug 2023 Jakarta, Indonesia Sept 2022 - Mar 2023 Jakarta, Indonesia

Jan 2020 - Present

Jakarta, Indonesia

Jakarta, Indonesia

Feb 2022 - July 2022

Aug 2019 - Aug 2023

### **SKILLS**

BE Engineer: Go (Golang), C++, Gorm, Gin, Redis, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, gRPC, protobuf, NoSQL, etc. ML Engineer: Python, NumPy, Pandas, TensorFlow, PyTorch, NLP, LSTM, RNN, DNN, Time Series, etc. Data Engineer: SQL Server, SSIS, SSMS, ETL, Grafana, Kibana, Web Scrapping, Database Migration

Other: Teamwork, Time Management, Teaching, Proactive Learning, Growth Mindset, etc.

## **PROJECTS**

# **E-Commerce (SEASELL) - Website**

Assign as Led for final project and work as a Back-End Engineer in the Shopee Trainee Program.

Tech stack: Go (Golang), Gorm, Gin, Redis, PostgreSQL, SMTP, Cron Job, etc.

Real Time Cryptocurrency (RTC) - Android

2022

2023

Work as Full Stack Android Developer in the final project for mobile programming courses.

Tech stack: Android Studio, Kotlin, Restful API

**Fruit & Vegetable Classification - Android** 

Work as Full Stack Developer in the capstone project for Bangkit Academy led by Google.

2022

Tech stack: Machine Learning, Android Studio, Google Cloud Platform

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Google: IT Automation with Python, Crash Course on Python, etc.	Certificates (02/2022 - Present)
Imperial College: Mathematics for Machine Learning Certificate, etc.	Certificates (03/2022 - Present)
<b>DeepLearningAl:</b> TensorFlow Developer, TensorFlow Data and Deployment, etc.	Certificates (04/2022 - Present)
Hackerrank: Problem Solving Intermediate, SQL Intermediate, etc.	Certificates (07/2021 - Present)
Sololearn: Python for Data Science, SQL, C++ etc.	Certificates (02/2022 - Present)
<b>Dicoding:</b> Machine Learning Mastery Evaluation, Kotlin Foundation etc.	Certificates (03/2022 - Present)
GeeksForGeeks: Python Facts, etc.	Certificates (12/2021 - Present)